<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Updates Feed</title>
    <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/</link>
    <description>Currently the Azure Updates page has no RSS enabled - this is a temp feed made by scraping that page for updates</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://mikesprague.github.io/azure-updates-feed/rss/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 12:02:53 GMT</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Jumpstart Drops</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467783</link>
      <description>Jumpstart Drops has officially reached general availability, marking a major milestone in simplifying workflows and empowering users exploring Microsoft technologies.&#160; Since its Public Preview debut at Microsoft Build 2024, Jumpstart Drops has grown into a thriving resource, with dozens of unique Drops, hundreds of downloads, and thousands of views contributed by our growing community.&#160; This launch introduces exciting new features, including a Drops Creation Wizard for seamless contributions, enhanced labeling for improved navigation, and various UI enhancements inspired by user feedback.&#160; To celebrate contributors who have gone above and beyond, we are also introducing "The Giver", a new badge in the Jumpstart Community Badges program, recognizing exceptional contributions that go above and beyond.  Explore, contribute, and share Jumpstart Drops today to help drive innovation and success across your teams.Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Jumpstart Agora Contoso Hypermarket</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467788</link>
      <description>Jumpstart Agora Contoso Hypermarket has officially reached general availability, showcasing how Azure Arc and Azure AI services empower digital transformation in the retail industry.&#160; This scenario brings next-gen innovations to life, such as AI-powered shopper analytics for real-time customer behavior insights, computer vision for enhanced store efficiency, and predictive inventory management with Microsoft Copilot.  By simulating Contoso Hypermarket operations, users can explore cutting-edge solutions like natural language querying, edge-to-cloud data pipelines, and IoT-driven operational analytics, all designed to enhance customer experiences and streamline retail workflows.&#160; Dive into this scenario today to discover how Azure technologies can transform retail operations and help businesses thrive in an evolving market.Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Windows Server 2025</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467828</link>
      <description>Windows Server 2025 is generally available. The latest Windows Server helps organizations optimize&#160;for the future while delivering the security, performance, and flexibility they need today. Drive productivity with seamless hybrid, multicloud&#160;and edge capabilities that adapt to business imperatives on-premises and in the cloud. Get ahead of what&#8217;s&#160;next with forward-looking threat protection, improved scalability and agility, and GPU partitioning that can enable ML and AI workloads.&#160;Improve performance while staying secure through features including: virtualization-based security (VBS) enclaves and key protection; security baselines with drift protection; increased scalability for Active Directory, and hotpatching&#160;to streamline security updates.*&#160;Get increased performance with GPU partitioning across VMs, larger VMs with support 240 TB of RAM and 2048 virtual processors, and software-defined storage enhancements including ReFS&#160;(Resilient File System) optimized deduplication.&#160;*Hotpatching&#160;for on-premises and multicloud&#160;Windows Server VMs is in preview. It will require an Azure Arc connection and subscription. Hotpatching&#160;in Windows Server Datacenter: Azure Edition continues to be free of charge.&#160;&#160;Learn more:&#160;

Product page&#160;&#160;Seismic
page&#160;&#160;Blog
post&#160;&#160;Documentation</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Hotpatching for Windows Server 2025</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467857</link>
      <description>Windows Server 2025 Standard and Datacenter edition&#8239;server hotpatching&#160;- security updates without reboots - is ready for your evaluation&#160;in preview.&#160;This feature will be a game changer; simpler change control, shorter patch windows, easier orchestration&#160;Hotpatches&#160;are OS security updates that don&#8217;t&#160;require a reboot. It works by patching the in-memory code of running processes without the need to restart the process. This gives you benefits like:&#160;Lower workload impact with fewer reboots. Instead of 12 mandatory reboots a year you&#8217;ll&#160;now only have&#8239;quarterly scheduled reboots&#8239;(with the rare possibility of reboots being required&#160;in a nominal Hotpatch&#160;month).&#160;Fewer binaries mean updates download and install faster while consuming fewer disk and CPU resources.&#160;Easier patch orchestration and change control.&#160;Integrated with the optional Azure Update Manager.&#160;*Hotpatching&#160;for on-premises and multicloud&#160;Windows Server VMs is in preview, and&#160;will be no additional&#160;charge while in preview. It will require an Azure Arc connection and, once GA, will be offered by&#160;subscription. Hotpatching&#160;in Windows Server Datacenter: Azure Edition continues to be free of charge.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Network security perimeter</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=469298</link>
      <description>Network security perimeter restricts communication to resources within the perimeter, and it allows non-perimeter public traffic through inbound and outbound access rules.&#160;With network security perimeter, administrators can:&#160;Create a secure boundary around PaaS resources.&#160;Prevent data exfiltration by associating PaaS resources to the perimeter.&#160;Enable access rules to grant access outside the secure perimeter.&#160;Manage access rules for all the PaaS resources within the network security perimeter in a single pane of glass.&#160;Enable diagnostic settings to generate access logs of PaaS resources within the perimeter for Audit and Compliance.&#160;Allow private endpoint traffic without additional&#160;access rules.Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=469298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Da/Ea/Fav6 series AMD based Azure Virtual Machines (VMs)</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467763</link>
      <description>Microsoft is announcing the general availability&#160;of the new Da/Ea/Fav6 series AMD based&#160;virtual machines (VMs). These&#160;VMs consist of our new general purpose Dasv6-series and Dalsv6-series, our new memory optimized Easv6-series VM series, and our new compute&#160;optimized Falsv6, Fasv6 and Famsv6 VM series. They offer better performance and better price-performance than our previous&#160;generation AMD based VMs, making them an attractive option&#160;for a wide range of workloads, including data analytics, web&#160;and application servers, databases, caches, and more.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;These VMs come with the NVMe&#160;interface for local and remote disks. Many workloads will benefit&#160;from improvements over the previous&#160;generation of AMD based with up to:&#160;80% better remote storage performance&#160;400% faster local storage speeds&#160;20% networking bandwidth improvement&#160;45% higher NVMe&#160;SSD capacity per vCPU for Daldsv6, Dadsv6, Eadsv6-series VMs with local disks&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467763</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: On-demand backups for Azure Database for PostgreSQL - Flexible Server</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467509</link>
      <description>Now you can create physical snapshots of Azure Database for PostgreSQL - Flexible Server based on your business needs. This feature complements&#160;the scheduled automated backups offered by the service, while adding&#160;the flexibility to delete&#160;the on-demand backups to help you manage costs effectively.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Introducing Apache AGE graph support in Azure Database for PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467524</link>
      <description>We&#8217;re&#160;excited to announce new Apache AGE support in Azure Database for PostgreSQL, a significant advancement in graph processing&#160;capabilities within the PostgreSQL ecosystem. You can now take full advantage of a powerful set of graph database tools using the robust enterprise features of Azure Database for PostgreSQL. Apache AGE enables you to move beyond baseline Retrieval Augmented Generation&#160;(RAG)&#160;application patterns to GraphRAG&#160;powered by Azure Database for PostgreSQL.&#160;&#160;&#160;Apache AGE provides&#160;graph database functionality, enabling you to store and query graph data efficiently within PostgreSQL. Using&#160;the intuitive openCypher&#160;query language, you can easily write expressive graph queries. In addition, you can manage and analyze complex relationships within your data, uncovering insights that traditional relational databases and even semantic search might miss.&#160;&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Default zone resilience in Azure Database for MySQL &#8211; Flexible Server Business Critical service tier</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467738</link>
      <description>In the face of zonal outages, ensuring seamless server recovery is critical for maintaining&#160;business continuity. With this new enhancement&#160;in Dec 2024, your mission-critical MySQL workloads on Azure Database for MySQL &#8211; Flexible Server Business Critical service tier are now zone-resilient by default&#8212;at no additional&#160;cost.&#160;Even if you don&#8217;t&#160;configure high availability&#160;(HA), Flexible Server will host&#160;your data and log files in zone-redundant storage by default. Existing servers configured for zone-redundant HA continue to benefit&#160;from the 99.99% uptime service&#160;level agreement (SLA)&#160;provided by built-in zonal&#160;redundancy and hot standby.&#160;In addition, servers configured for same-zone HA and non-HA also benefit&#8212;they&#160;can recover quickly from zonal outages using the zone-redundant backups.&#160;&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Standby Pools for Virtual Machine Scale Sets with Flexible Orchestration</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=468335</link>
      <description>Standby Pools for Virtual Machine Scale Sets with Flexible
Orchestration is now generally available. &#160;Standby pools for Virtual Machine Scale Sets enables you to
increase scaling performance by creating a pool of pre-provisioned virtual
machines. The virtual machines in the standby pool complete all post
provisioning processes such as installing applications, downloading data
packages, etc. Once the virtual machines have been fully provisioned, they can
be maintained in a running or a stopped (deallocated) state. When your scale
set requires more instances, the instances in the standby pool are automatically
moved into the scale set. A standby pool significantly reduces the time it
takes to scale out a Virtual Machine Scale Set.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=468335</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Private Preview: Web Application Firewall (WAF) running on Application Gateway for Containers</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=468587</link>
      <description>Application Gateway for
Containers now supports Web Application Firewall (WAF) in private preview. WAF&#8217;s
Default Ruleset provides Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) users with centralized
protection against malicious attacks and exploits such as:&#160;
 Cross-site scripting&#160;
 Java attacks&#160;
 Local file inclusion&#160;
 PHP injection attacks&#160;
 Remote command execution&#160;
 Remote file inclusion&#160;
 Session fixation&#160;
 SQL injection protection&#160;
 Protocol attacks&#160;Additionally, Application
Gateway for Containers WAF also supports protection against malicious bot
activity via the bot manager rulesets.&#160;If you&#8217;re interested
in signing up for this private preview, please fill out this intake form to start the
onboarding process.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=468587</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Entra ID support for SSH connections in portal</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=entra-id-support-for-ssh-connections-in-portal-is-now-generally-available</link>
      <description>We are announcing that Azure Bastion now supports Microsoft Entra ID authentication for SSH connections in the portal. With Microsoft Entra ID authentication, there are two main benefits to users connecting to their virtual machines. First, it eliminates the need for local authentication mechanisms, reducing a point of attack for malicious actors.&#160; Second, with Microsoft Entra ID authentication set as the authentication mechanism, instead of providing additional authentication to connect, users can experience a one-click sign-on into their virtual machines.Learn more about Microsoft Entra IDLearn to configure Entra ID for SSH connections</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=entra-id-support-for-ssh-connections-in-portal-is-now-generally-available</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Network isolated cluster in AKS</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466980</link>
      <description>Today you can
control an AKS cluster's egress traffic using Azure Firewall. While this
configuration is intended to isolate the cluster to protect sensitive business
or customer data, it adds an additional layer of management complexity and
cost. &#160;AKS now provides the
option to use network isolated clusters to simplify the process of restricting
network access and reduce the risk of unintentional exposure of the cluster's
public endpoints to prevent security breaches. &#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466980</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Azure API Center Plugin for GitHub Copilot for Azure</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=469053</link>
      <description>GitHub Copilot has rapidly become a favorite among developers, thanks to its conversational chat interface and seamless IDE integration. Recently, GitHub Copilot for Azure&#160;was introduced to streamline development on the Azure platform, making it an excellent choice for Azure-related tasks.&#160;We are thrilled to announce the public preview of an Azure API Center&#160;plugin for GitHub Copilot for Azure&#160;(@azure)!&#160;&#160;With the public preview of the API Center plugin, you can now leverage GitHub Copilot for Azure for a variety of API-related tasks:&#160;Generating API Specifications: Simply describe your requirements in natural language, and GitHub Copilot for Azure will create new API specifications tailored to your needs. It can also help you register these APIs into the API Center swiftly.&#160;Designing Compliant APIs: Use GitHub Copilot for Azure to design API specifications that comply with API Center governance. The AI assistance ensures that your APIs are designed according to best practices and standards&#160;&#160;We invite you to explore the public preview and experience how the Azure API Center plugin for GitHub Copilot for Azure can enhance your development workflow. Join us in this exciting journey to make API development smarter and more efficient!</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=469053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Advanced Container Networking Services</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466985</link>
      <description>We&#8217;re announcing&#160;the general availability of Advanced Container Networking Service&#160;for Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS), a cloud native purpose-built&#160;solution to enhance security and observability for Kubernetes and containerized environments.&#160;Advanced Container Networking Service focuses on delivering a seamless and integrated experience that enables you to maintain robust security postures, ensure comprehensive compliance and gain deep insights into your network traffic and application performance.&#160;&#160;Advanced Container Networking Service delivers observability features tailored specifically for AKS. Advanced Container Networking Service offers network metrics at&#160;node-level, pod-level, and at L4 with DNS and TCP statistics&#160;ensuring that no aspect of your network goes unnoticed. These metrics are critical for identifying performance bottlenecks and resolving network issues before they impact your services.&#160;This is in addition to&#160;Hubble&#160;Flow Logs,&#160;which&#160;gives you end to end visibility into workload communication&#160;to understand how&#160;microservices are communicating with&#160;each other. Using Hubble UI,&#160;you can visualize the traffic by creating&#160;a service-dependency&#160;graph.&#160;&#160;&#160;On the security side,&#160;Advanced Container Networking Service provides FQDN filtering capabilities for network policy, designed specifically to simplify and strengthen external communication security.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466985</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Extension of limited-time promotional discounts on Azure Databricks Serverless Compute Services</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467457</link>
      <description>We&#8217;re excited to announce the extension of the promotional discounts on serverless compute for Notebooks, Jobs, and Pipelines (Delta Live Tables). You will continue to get 50% off serverless compute for Jobs and Pipelines and 30% off serverless compute for Notebooks, until&#160;January 31, 2025.&#160;Serverless compute provides rapid workload startup, automatic infrastructure scaling, and seamless version upgrades of the Azure Databricks runtime.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retirement: End of Support Announcement for Azure Load Balancer numberOfProbes property on September 1, 2027.</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=end-of-support-announcement-for-azure-load-balancer-numberofprobes-property-on-1-september-2027</link>
      <description>Support for Azure Load Balancer numberOfProbes property ends on September 1, 2027. To avoid service disruption, upgrade your apps to API version 2022-05-01 or higher and start using Azure Load Balancer probeThreshold property. We will not be supporting the property numberOfProbes after September 1, 2027.Required actionBefore September 1, 2027, stop using the property numberOfProbes and/or migrate to probeThreshold property.Learn more about updating your API.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=end-of-support-announcement-for-azure-load-balancer-numberofprobes-property-on-1-september-2027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TLS 1.2 to become the minimum TLS version for Azure Storage</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=tls-12-to-become-the-minimum-tls-version-for-azure-storage</link>
      <description>To respond to evolving technology and regulatory standards, Azure Storage will remove support for TLS version 1.1 and 1.0, and the minimum supported version will be TLS1.2 starting November 1, 2025. TLS 1.2 is more secure and faster than older TLS versions. TLS 1.0 and 1.1 do not support modern cryptographic algorithms and cipher suites.&#160;&#160;

This change impacts existing and new storage accounts using TLS 1.0 and 1.1 in all clouds. To avoid disruptions to your applications connecting to Azure Storage, you must migrate to TLS 1.2 and remove dependencies on TLS version 1.0 and 1.1.&#160;

Azure Storage already supports TLS 1.2 which is set as the default. Customers using TLS 1.2 will not be impacted by the removal of support for TLS 1.0 and 1.1. For customers using TLS 1.0 or 1.1, to maintain your connections to Azure Storage, please update your operating systems, development libraries, frameworks, and all other solutions to their latest versions to support TLS 1.2 and update your clients to TLS 1.2 no later than Oct 31st, 2025.&#8239;&#160;

We have compiled a series of recommendations and resources to help with your migration:&#160;Navigate here for more information</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=tls-12-to-become-the-minimum-tls-version-for-azure-storage</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Azure Cosmos DB vector database integration with LangChain.js</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466855</link>
      <description>We&#8217;re&#160;excited to introduce LangChain.js integration with Azure Cosmos DB. You can use this powerful combination to efficiently manage fast and accurate&#160;data retrieval with greater ease in your JavaScript applications. The new LangChain.js integration makes the most of Azure Cosmos DB scalability and efficient vector search capabilities, simplifying applications development and large language model (LLM) orchestration tasks.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466855</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Single prefix enhancement to seamless gateway migration</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467620</link>
      <description>With the Gateway migration experience, customers can use the Azure Portal or PowerShell scripts to deploy a second Virtual Network Gateway within the same GatewaySubnet of the Virtual Network. During the migration phase, once initiated by the customer, Azure will transfer both the control plane and data path configurations from the existing gateway to the newly deployed one. This process will result in two operational Gateways within the same Gateway Subnet. After the migration is successfully completed, customers can remove the original Gateway, leaving the new Gateway in place for continued Private Connectivity.&#160;Previously, ExpressRoute Gateway customers needed to create a second address prefix to pass the validation stage of migrating their gateway. With this enhancement, customers can now migrate with a single prefix, eliminating the previous requirement to create a second address prefix in the Gateway. This feature is designed to support migrations with minimal downtime.To learn more, see:About migrating to an availability zone-enabled ExpressRoute virtual network gateway - Azure ExpressRoute | Microsoft LearnMigrate to an availability zone-enabled ExpressRoute virtual network gateway in Azure portal - Azure ExpressRoute | Microsoft Learn</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467620</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
