<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Updates Feed</title>
    <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/</link>
    <description>Currently the Azure Updates page has no RSS enabled - this is a temp feed made by scraping that page for updates</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://mikesprague.github.io/azure-updates-feed/rss/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 12:03:09 GMT</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Enhancements on Azure Container Storage for performance, scalability, and operational insights</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=469776</link>
      <description>We are excited to unveil key advancements in Azure Container Storage, our purpose-built storage solution for stateful containers on Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS). These updates bring increased performance and improved reliability to support even the most demanding containerized applications.&#160;We have optimized&#160;ephemeral disk performance to improve read&#160;and write&#160;IOPS. These enhancements include updates to local NVMe&#160;performance both with and without replication, detailed here:&#160;&#160;Optimize performance when using local NVMe&#160;without replication.&#160;Optimize performance when using local NVMe&#160;with replication. &#160;&#160;To learn more about our latest version release, check out the Release notes.&#160;With these new capabilities, Azure Container Storage empowers you&#160;to achieve optimal&#160;performance, visibility, and resilience, making it an even stronger choice for deploying scalable, containerized applications in the cloud. Join us at Ignite to explore how these updates can elevate your cloud storage strategy!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=469776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Kubernetes Metadata and Logs Filtering in Azure Monitor - Container Insights</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=469519</link>
      <description>We are excited to announce the general availability of
Kubernetes Metadata and Logs Filtering in Azure Monitor &#8211; Container Insights!
This enhancement adds Kubernetes metadata to the ContainerLogsV2 schema,
including PodLabels, PodAnnotations, PodUid, Image, ImageID, ImageRepo, and
ImageTag. Users can customize metadata fields via ConfigMap, and all fields are
collected by default. The new Logs Filtering feature allows for precise
filtering of both workload and system pods/containers. Additionally, the enhanced
ContainerLogV2 schema includes log level information to assess application
health with color-coded severity levels. A Grafana Dashboard is available for
visualizing log levels, log volume, rate, records, and more, empowering
in-depth analysis and real-time monitoring. These advancements provide users
with richer context and improved visibility into their workloads.&#160;&#160;To learn more and enable the Kubernetes Logs Metadata and Filtering
experience, follow the steps here.&#160;If you have any questions or feedback on Kubernetes Logs Metadata and
Filtering, please reach out to ibraraslam@microsoft.com or fill out this survey!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=469519</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Cross-region replication in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=mdb-vcore-repl</link>
      <description>With new support&#160;for cross-region disaster recovery in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB, you can create a replica of a cluster&#160;in another region. This cluster replica is continuously updated with the data written in the primary region. In the&#160;rare case of an outage in the primary region, you can promote this replica to become the new read-write cluster. &#160;&#160; &#160;You can also use the cluster replica in another region for reading. This helps offload read operations from the primary cluster and deliver reads with lower latency to applications that are hosted closer to the other region. &#160;&#160; &#160;When the cluster replica in region B is promoted and becomes the new read-write cluster, it mirrors the original configuration by maintaining&#160;a read replica in the former primary region A. The global read-write connection string always points to the cluster available for writes. It allows uninterrupted work with the database after replica cluster promotion.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=mdb-vcore-repl</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB multishard clusters</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=mdb-vcore-sharding</link>
      <description>You can now use up to five physical shards on your vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB clusters. An increased number of shards&#160;in a cluster enables you to host larger workloads and get elevated performance through higher concurrency.&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;When you create a vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB cluster, you can select from one to five shards. As before, each physical shard gets the same compute&#160;(vCore&#160;count and amount of RAM) and storage (GiB and IOPS) configuration. &#160;&#160;&#160;Using a greater number of physical shards can also help increase cluster performance for larger workloads that require multishard&#160;clusters because of better parallelization.&#160;&#160;Learn more</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=mdb-vcore-sharding</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB&#8212;up to 32 TiB storage</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb-up-to-32-tib-storage</link>
      <description>Higher capacity&#160;storage with higher IOPS enables you to host larger workloads on your vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB cluster. Now when you provision new clusters, you can help elevate performance by choosing from 8 TiB, 16 TiB, and 32 TiB with 16,000 IOPS, 18,000 IOPS, and 20,000 IOPS&#160;respectively. You can also scale up existing clusters using any of the new storage sizes as your workloads grow. &#160;&#160;When you combine these new options with multiple physical shards in your vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB cluster, your large storage capacity&#160;can comfortably handle hundreds of terabytes of data.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=vcore-based-azure-cosmos-db-for-mongodb-up-to-32-tib-storage</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: DiskANN indexing on Azure Database for PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=diskann-indexing-on-azure-database-for-postgresql</link>
      <description>We're thrilled to announce the preview of DiskANN, one of the fastest vector indexing algorithms on the market, which is now available for Azure Database for PostgreSQL. Developed at Microsoft Research, DiskANN is used extensively at Microsoft in global services such as Bing and Microsoft 365.DiskANN enables you to build highly accurate, performant, and scalable generative AI applications that surpass pgvector&#8217;s HNSW and IVFFlat indexes in both speed and accuracy. DiskANN also overcomes a long-standing limitation of pgvector in filtered vector search, where it occasionally returns incorrect results.Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=diskann-indexing-on-azure-database-for-postgresql</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Mirroring Azure SQL Database in Fabric</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=public-preview-azure-sql-database-mirroring-in-microsoft-fabric</link>
      <description>We are excited to announce the general availability of Mirroring Azure SQL Database in Fabric. Mirroring is a simple, free,&#160;and frictionless way to replicate a snapshot of incremental data changes in Azure SQL Database to Fabric OneLake.&#160;Delta tables keep your data in sync&#160;in near-real time. Mirroring is a low-cost, zero-code, zero-ETL solution&#160;that brings data together, driving faster time to insight.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=public-preview-azure-sql-database-mirroring-in-microsoft-fabric</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Data API in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467485</link>
      <description>We&#8217;re&#160;excited to announce the public preview of the Data API for vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB. The Data&#160;API provides a flexible and powerful way to interact with your database through HTTP-based API calls.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Empowering teams with new features in Microsoft Dev Box</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=468062</link>
      <description>We're announcing new features in Dev Box that make it
easier to configure task-based workstations for development teams and enhance project
guardrails. &#160;Cloud-based development environment for teams&#160;Team customizations: Dev team leads can create project-based
configurations for their entire team, with the tools, packages and settings in
a single config file. (Preview)&#160;Run-as-user support for team
customizations enable team leads to execute as-user customizations for more
ready-to-code dev boxes.&#160;Imaging: Dev team leads can now convert team
customizations into images, reducing provisioning time for new dev boxes,
removing the need for custom image pipelines, and enabling automatic upstream OS
updates. (Preview)&#160;Dev
Box customizations and imaging now support secrets and variables,
enabling teams to reuse centralized secrets stored in Azure Key Vault, private
repos, or private artifact servers, and work more securely.&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;Built for enterprise trust&#160;Project Policy. IT
Admins can set up guardrails around resources that projects can and cannot
access, such as images, SKUs, and network connections. (Preview)&#160;Learn more in our announcement blog, tune in to the breakout
Tuesday, November 19 at 1:30 PM Central time: Beyond VDI: Get secure cloud dev environment with Dev Box, and get started today!</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=468062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: DiskANN vector indexing and search in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467434</link>
      <description>We&#8217;re&#160;excited to announce the public preview of DiskANN&#160;with filtering&#160;in vCore-based Azure Cosmos DB for MongoDB. With DiskANN, you can perform large-scale vector searches while reducing memory usage by up to 10&#160;times&#160;compared to other algorithms&#160;like IVFFlat&#160;and HNSW&#8212;making recommendation engines,&#160;fraud detection, and other AI applications&#160;more cost-effective and scalable. Enjoy low-latency, high-availability performance, even with billions of vectors.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467434</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Private Preview: Azure Confidential Clean Rooms</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467753</link>
      <description>Microsoft is announcing the gated preview of&#160;Azure Confidential Clean Rooms, a cutting-edge&#160;solution designed for organizations that require secure multi-party data collaboration. With Confidential Clean Rooms, you can share privacy sensitive data such as personally identifiable information (PII), protected health information (PHI) and cryptographic secrets confidently, thanks to robust trust guarantees that safeguard your data throughout its lifecycle from other collaborators and from Azure operators. This secure data sharing is powered by confidential computing, which protects data in-use by performing computations in hardware-based, attested Trusted Execution Environments (TEEs). These TEEs help prevent unauthorized access or modification of application code and data during use.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467753</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: .NET 9</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467290</link>
      <description>As of November 12, 2024, NET 9 is now generally available for download. Azure PaaS services, including Azure App Service, Azure Functions, Azure Container Apps, and more, now fully support .NET 9.Customers can now leverage the enhanced capabilities of .NET 9, such as significant performance improvements, adaptive garbage collection, and support for ARM64 optimizations, to build and deploy cloud-native and AI-powered applications more efficiently. They can also take advantage of seamless integration with Azure services to scale and manage their .NET 9 applications with improved observability and reduced cloud costs.Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Azure NetApp Files cool access support for large volumes</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467748</link>
      <description>Announcing the general availability of cool access feature support with large volumes. This allows tiering of infrequently accessed data on large volumes under standard, premium or ultra storage, to a lower-cost storage tier. &#160;This allows your large capacity workloads to take advantage of cost savings for the inactive data. The seamless integration with all service levels extends the capabilities of cool access to large data repositories that must be kept online for compliance/business processes, providing major cost optimization in Oil &#38;Gas, Manufacturing and HealthCare areas. All the features supported with cool access can now be used with large volumes of size ranging anywhere from 50 TiB to 1 PiB (up to 2 PiB on request). This capability will be supported only in the ANF regions where large volumes are supported.Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467748</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Spot Placement Score</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=468359</link>
      <description>Today, we are announcing the public preview of Azure Spot
Placement Score, a feature designed to help you assess the likelihood of
success for your Spot VM deployments.&#160;
Given that Spot availability can fluctuate based on SKU size, location,
availability zones, or time of day, Spot Placement Score provides the ability
to evaluate the chance of deployment success by assigning a rating of High,
Medium, or Low to a Spot VM size before deployment.&#160; This feature provides increased clarity and
control, enabling you to make more informed decisions about which Spot VMs to
deploy and where.Using Spot Placement Score, you can achieve the following: &#160;A clear evaluation of how likely your Spot deployments is
to succeed based on specified parameters. &#160;Identify the most suitable combination of regions and VM
sizes to maximize Spot VM availability and survivability based on placement
scores. &#160;Improve the overall success rate of deploying Spot VMs by
leveraging data-driven placement scores, reducing the risk of capacity issues
or failures during deployment.&#160;You can sign up for access in the and learn more in the blog and documentation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=468359</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Index tuning in Azure Database for PostgreSQL - Flexible Server</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=public-preview-index-recommendations-in-azure-database-for-postgresql-flexible-server</link>
      <description>Now you can use index&#160;tuning to analyze&#160;the most resource intensive set of queries in your workload and produce&#160;recommendations of indexes that, once created, improve the performance of those queries. Index tuning also recommends indexes you can drop if they are identified as duplicates or are considered irrelevant for lack of use.&#160;&#160;&#160;The new index tuning feature builds on query store in Azure Database for PostgreSQL - Flexible Server, which captures and retains&#160;a history of queries executed in your workload and the runtime statistics of those queries.&#160;&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=public-preview-index-recommendations-in-azure-database-for-postgresql-flexible-server</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Azure Managed Redis</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467264</link>
      <description>As your applications scale, fast and reliable data access becomes critical. Now in public preview, Azure Managed Redis brings the latest Redis innovations with enhanced availability while being more&#160;cost-effective.&#160;Azure Managed Redis boosts AI application performance, supports session management, and interoperates seamlessly with various Azure services.&#160;&#160;With four new tiers, you can now customize your Redis solution to match specific performance and memory requirements. Azure Managed Redis also delivers up to 99.999% availability* for uninterrupted access to mission-critical apps, while offering enterprise-level security and password-free authentication through Microsoft Entra ID.&#160;&#160;*Up to 99.999% availability is planned for general availability of Azure Managed Redis.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Full text and hybrid search in Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467425</link>
      <description>Now you can use Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL to power more generative AI scenarios and to build applications with advanced search capabilities. We are thrilled to announce three new search features in Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL, now available in public preview:&#160;Full-text search: Perform efficient text searches on your data with advanced text analysis capabilities, including&#160;tokenization and stemming. Currently supports English, with more languages coming soon.&#160;BM25 text ranking: Enhance your text search relevance with BM25 ranking, which considers term frequency, document length, and term importance to find the most relevant documents in a text search&#160;Hybrid search: Combine your vector searches with BM25-based text ranking for highly accurate&#160;and contextually relevant results. This feature uses Reciprocal Rank Fusion (RRF) to merge and rank the results for improved relevancy.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467425</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Solution Accelerator for building a legal research copilot using GraphRAG on Azure Database for PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467533</link>
      <description>Accuracy of the information retrieval pipeline plays a key role in the quality of Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) applications. GraphRAG&#160;is one of the advanced RAG techniques that improves accuracy of the information retrieval using graph-like relationships in your data. This solution accelerator shows you how to build a legal research copilot using this advanced technique on top of Azure Database for PostgreSQL.&#160;&#160;&#160;This solution accelerator integrates GraphRAG&#160;with PostgreSQL graph query capabilities,&#160;providing a complete GraphRAG&#160;platform with a minimal number of platform components. The solution accelerator uses a semantic ranker for relevance boosting, the Apache AGE extension for graph queries, and the azure_ai&#160;extension for integration with Azure AI Services,&#160;including Azure OpenAI.&#160;&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Semantic Ranker Solution Accelerator on Azure Database for PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467538</link>
      <description>Accuracy of the information retrieval&#160;pipeline plays a key role in the quality of advanced Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) applications. Using the new Semantic Ranker Solution Accelerator,&#160;you can extend Azure Database for PostgreSQL&#160;with a semantic ranker&#160;model and use it directly in PostgreSQL queries&#160;to boost accuracy of the vector search results.&#160;&#160;&#160;This solution accelerator&#160;provides automated deployment scripts&#160;that you can use to provision a semantic ranker model as an Azure Machine Learning inference endpoint.&#160;It also includes SQL user-defined functions for PostgreSQL&#160;that you can use to integrate the semantic ranker model into SQL queries. &#160;&#160;This solution accelerator&#160;requires azure_ai&#160;extension.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467538</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Vector search in Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467543</link>
      <description>Now generally available in Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL, vector search enables your applications to perform high-dimensional vector similarity searches. You can take advantage of advanced AI scenarios including semantic search, Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG), semantic caching, and anomaly detection. This release also improves performance, including faster vector ingestion and lower search latencies,&#160;and offers compatibility with popular Azure Cosmos DB for NoSQL capabilities,&#160;such as customer-managed keys, continuous backup, point-in-time restore, and Fabric mirroring. Operational and vector data stays&#160;together and in sync, simplifying your data management, AI application architectures, and vector-based operations.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467543</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
