<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Updates Feed</title>
    <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/</link>
    <description>Currently the Azure Updates page has no RSS enabled - this is a temp feed made by scraping that page for updates</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://mikesprague.github.io/azure-updates-feed/rss/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 12:02:46 GMT</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Extension of limited-time promotional discounts on Azure Databricks Serverless Compute Services</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467457</link>
      <description>We&#8217;re excited to announce the extension of the promotional discounts on serverless compute for Notebooks, Jobs, and Pipelines (Delta Live Tables). You will continue to get 50% off serverless compute for Jobs and Pipelines and 30% off serverless compute for Notebooks, until&#160;April 30, 2025.&#160;Serverless compute provides rapid workload startup, automatic infrastructure scaling, and seamless version upgrades of the Azure Databricks runtime.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Storage account default maximum request rate limit increase to 40,000 requests per second</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=470595</link>
      <description>The default maximum request rate for general-purpose v2 and
Blob storage accounts has been increased from 20,000 to 40,000 requests per
second in the following regions:&#160;&#160;
 East Asia&#160;&#160;
 Southeast Asia&#160;&#160;
 Australia East&#160;&#160;
 Brazil South&#160;&#160;
 Canada Central&#160;&#160;
 China East 2&#160;&#160;
 China North 3&#160;&#160;
 North Europe&#160;&#160;
 West Europe&#160;&#160;
 France Central&#160;&#160;
 Germany West
     Central&#160;&#160;
 Central India&#160;&#160;
 Japan East&#160;&#160;
 Jio India West&#160;&#160;
 Korea Central&#160;&#160;
 Norway East&#160;&#160;
 South Africa North&#160;&#160;
 Sweden Central&#160;&#160;
 UAE North&#160;&#160;
 UK South&#160;&#160;
 Central US&#160;&#160;
 East US&#160;&#160;
 East US 2&#160;&#160;
 USGov Virginia&#160;&#160;
 USGov Arizona&#160;&#160;
 North Central US&#160;&#160;
 South Central US&#160;&#160;
 West US&#160;&#160;
 West US 2&#160;&#160;
 West US 3&#160;&#160;This applies to all existing and new storage accounts.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=470595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Private Preview: Azure Automation is revising Service and Subscription limits</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471605</link>
      <description>Starting&#8239;January 7th,&#160;2025, Azure Automation will be revising its Service and Subscription limits to ensure fair distribution of cloud resources across all customers. The current Service and Subscription limits for Azure Automation can be found&#8239;here.&#160;&#160;Revised limits:&#160;Resource&#160;Limit&#160;Notes&#160;Maximum number of active Automation accounts in a subscription&#160;10&#160;&#8239;&#160;&#8239;2&#160;&#8239;&#160;&#8239;&#8239;&#160;&#8239;&#160;1&#160;&#8239;&#160;&#8239;&#160;&#8239;&#160;Enterprise and CSP subscriptions&#160;&#160;&#160;Pay-as-you-go, Sponsored, MSDN, MPN, Azure Pass subscriptions&#160;&#160;Free trial, Azure for Student, Azure in Open subscriptions can create only one Automation account per region per subscription, in 6 allowed&#160;regions.&#160;Maximum number of concurrent running jobs at the same instance of time per Automation account&#160;50&#160;&#160;&#8239;10&#160;&#160;&#160;5&#160;Enterprise and CSP subscriptions&#160;&#160;Pay-as-you-go, Sponsored, MSDN, MPN, Azure Pass subscriptions&#160;&#160;Free trial, Azure for Student, Azure in Open subscriptions&#160;Note:&#160;You will be able to check your limits and request for increase by&#160;creating a support request under the category &#8216;Service and Subscription limits (Quotas)&#8217;&#160;-&#62; &#8216;Azure Automation&#8217;.&#8239;This capability is under development and&#160;will be enabled in January 2025.&#160;Your current usage will be honored if it is more than the revised limits. For example,&#160;if&#160;your current usage is 12 Automation accounts and the new limit&#160;is 10, you could continue using all&#160;12 accounts. To create&#160;more accounts, you will have&#160;to request for&#160;quota. Detailed steps for requesting&#160;quota changes would be shared in January 2025.Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471605</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Network isolated cluster in AKS</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466980</link>
      <description>Today you can
control an AKS cluster's egress traffic using Azure Firewall. While this
configuration is intended to isolate the cluster to protect sensitive business
or customer data, it adds an additional layer of management complexity and
cost. &#160;AKS now provides the
option to use network isolated clusters to simplify the process of restricting
network access and reduce the risk of unintentional exposure of the cluster's
public endpoints to prevent security breaches. &#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466980</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Introducing security baseline with auto-remediation for Linux hybrid workloads</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=469654</link>
      <description>The new Azure security baseline for Linux provides enhanced monitoring of compliance status across Linux workloads. It offers more accurate&#160;and detailed compliance information and helps customers meet regulatory requirements faster. Combined with the auto-remediation capabilities, it will offer a holistic approach&#160;across hybrid environments to deal with continuous compliance and hardening on Linux workloads.&#160;Key highlights of the Azure security baseline for Linux:&#160;Provided at no cost,&#160;except for the Azure Arc workloads (on-prem / other CSP).&#160;Enhanced compliance experience with more accurate&#160;state (Public Preview).&#160;Detailed information about the state of compliance (Public Preview)&#160;Fully open-sourced engine for compliance and remediation (Public Preview).&#160;Auto-remediation capabilities against the security baseline (Limited Public Preview).&#160;&#160;The auto-remediation capability&#160;will be&#160;available as a limited public&#160;preview&#160;in selected regions. If you&#160;are interested in participating&#160;in the preview,&#8239;you&#160;can request access&#8239;to get started.&#8239; &#160;Learn more:Read our blog.Refer to the documentation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=469654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Parallel Image Pulls by Default in AKS</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471237</link>
      <description>There
are two types of container image pulls: serialized and parallel.&#160;&#160;By default, AKS
versions earlier than 1.31 use serialized image pulls. Starting with AKS
version 1.31 preview, AKS defaults to parallel image pulls. Generally,
serialized image pulls are less performant than parallel pulls, especially when
dealing with large or numerous container images. This update helps to enhance
overall system efficiency.Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: IMDS restriction support in AKS</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471270</link>
      <description>Currently, all
pods on AKS nodes can access the AKS worker node's Azure Instance Metadata
Service (IMDS) endpoint.&#160;AKS now offers a
managed solution that restricts IMDS endpoint access for customer pods. Only
AKS system pods and user pods with host network can access IMDS for retrieving
information or authentication.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: AKS Communication Manager</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471275</link>
      <description>The AKS Communication Manager,
now in public preview, simplifies notifications for all your AKS maintenance
tasks by leveraging Azure Resource Notification and Azure Resource Graph
frameworks.&#160;&#160;It provides timely alerts on
event triggers and outcomes, allowing you to closely monitor your upgrades. In
case of maintenance failures, it notifies you with the reasons for the failure,
reducing operational hassles related to observability and follow-ups.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Windows GPU &#8211; Driver type selection</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471280</link>
      <description>AKS now supports GPU-enabled
Windows node pools, in public preview, to run compute-intensive Kubernetes
workloads. AKS specifies a default GPU driver type for each supported
GPU-enabled VM. Because workload and driver compatibility are important for
functioning GPU workloads, you can now specify the driver type for your Windows
GPU node. &#160;When creating a Windows agent
pool with GPU support, you have the option to specify the type of GPU driver
using the --driver-type flag.&#160;The available options are:&#160;GRID: For applications
requiring virtualization support.&#160;CUDA: Optimized for
computational tasks in scientific computing and data-intensive applications. &#160;&#160;This feature is currently not
supported for Linux GPU node pools.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471280</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Open-source feature update: vLLM model serving in KAITO</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471285</link>
      <description>KAITO
now supports high throughput model serving with the open-source vLLM serving
engine. In the KAITO inference workspace, you can deploy models using vLLM to
batch process incoming requests, accelerate inference, and optimize your AI
workload by default, preventing out-of-memory (OOM) errors and minimizing workload
disruptions.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: KAITO managed add-on now available in the AKS Visual Studio Code extension</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471290</link>
      <description>The AI toolchain operator (KAITO) managed add-on is now available in the
Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) Visual Studio Code extension. With an intuitive
and visually engaging UI, this add-on is designed to simplify AI inference development.
Customers can enable KAITO, browse through the supported options, and choose an
open-source AI model to deploy to their AKS cluster. Once deployed, they can access model logs,
test performance, and fully engage with the model workspace directly from
VSCode.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Force attach/detach API support in AKS</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471295</link>
      <description>With the release of Kubernetes v1.30, the Azure Disk
CSI driver has adopted the force detach capability. This feature allows the driver
to force detach zone-redundant storage (ZRS) data disks from VM nodes in a
failed zone and attach them to another VM, reducing the Recovery Time Objective
(RTO).Stateful workloads in AKS clusters can now quickly
recover from zone failures by detaching ZRS data disks from affected VM nodes
and reattaching them to new VMs.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Vaulted backup for AKS</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471300</link>
      <description>Azure Backup now
supports vaulted backups for AKS, enabling cross-region disaster recovery,
long-term retention and immutable security. &#160;This simplifies compliance and strengthens
resilience for cloud-native applications.&#160;Customers can protect
clusters during a regional disaster recovery, store backup data for up to 10
years to meet compliance requirements, and secure backup data at an offsite
location to safeguard against ransomware threats.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471300</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: AKS support for private ingress on cluster create or through API</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471309</link>
      <description>When you enable the application routing add-on with NGINX, it
creates an ingress controller configured with a public facing Azure Load
Balancer. Starting with Kubernetes 1.30, you can control this behavior when
enabling the add-on by choosing if it gets a public or an internal IP.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: AKS automated deployments UI</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471319</link>
      <description>The AKS automated
deployments feature has received UI updates designed to make it easier for
customers to get started with Azure Kubernetes Service. With these new
improvements, you can now select specific locations for saving autogenerated
Dockerfiles and Kubernetes manifest files. With automated deployments, you can
easily get your apps up and running on Azure Kubernetes Service.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: GitHub Copilot for Azure &#8211; AKS plugins</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471324</link>
      <description>GitHub Copilot for Azure now supports Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)
plugins. The extension, which enables AKS plugins for GitHub Copilot for Azure
(@azure), allows users to perform various tasks related to AKS directly from
the GitHub Copilot Chat view. These tasks include creating an AKS cluster,
deploying a manifest to an AKS cluster, and generating Kubectl commands. &#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Enhanced AKS logs with Kubernetes metadata and logs filtering</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471329</link>
      <description>Azure
Kubernetes Service (AKS) logs now include detailed metadata, such as PodLabels,
PodAnnotations, PodUid, Image, ImageID, ImageRepo, and ImageTag. These
additions provide richer context and improved visibility into workloads, aiding
in troubleshooting and monitoring. The integration with Grafana further
enhances this by enabling users to visualize and analyze logs more effectively,
utilizing Grafana's powerful dashboard capabilities.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Microsoft Azure now available from new cloud region in New Zealand</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471035</link>
      <description>The first cloud region in New Zealand is now available&#160;with&#160;Azure&#160;Availability Zones&#160;and provides organizations across the globe with access to scalable, highly available, and resilient Microsoft Cloud services while confirming&#160;its&#160;commitment to promoting digital transformation and sustainable innovation in the country. The New Zealand region connects New Zealand to the largest and trusted global cloud infrastructure, delivering the&#160;highest standards of security, privacy and regulatory-compliant data storage in the country.&#160;For customers looking to leverage the new region and Availability Zones,&#160;Azure&#160;offers region portability for multiple resources with&#160;Azure&#160;Resource Mover.Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=471035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retirement: Azure CDN Standard/Premium from Edgio (formerly Verizon) will be retired</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467688</link>
      <description>All Azure CDN from Edgio customers must migrate their workloads to&#160;Azure Front Door&#160;or other CDN services before January 15, 2025 as Edgio has advised their platform is currently scheduled to be shut down by that date. Migrate as soon as possible to avoid an imminent service shut-down.Microsoft's flagship CDN product, Azure Front Door Standard or Premium, is our recommended replacement and we encourage you to consider migrating your compatible workloads there.&#160;View the comparison&#160;between Azure Front Door and Azure CDN from Edgio. Azure Front Door compatible workloads can use&#160;these step-by-step instructions.For more details, please visit our learn page&#160;here&#160;and/or contact Microsoft Support.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: High-availability health status monitoring for Azure Database for PostgreSQL &#8211; Flexible Server</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=470442</link>
      <description>With the general availability of high-availability (HA) health status monitoring for Azure Database for PostgreSQL &#8211;&#160;Flexible Server, you can now track and maintain&#160;the health of HA-enabled instances with ease. This feature offers real-time insights into the readiness of your primary and standby replicas, helping you proactively identify&#160;and address any issues impacting&#160;availability or failover capability. Based on the Azure Resource Health Check framework, this monitoring solution enables you to optimize&#160;uptime and minimize potential disruptions to your database services.&#160;&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=470442</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
