<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Updates Feed</title>
    <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/</link>
    <description>Currently the Azure Updates page has no RSS enabled - this is a temp feed made by scraping that page for updates</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://mikesprague.github.io/azure-updates-feed/rss/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 12:02:59 GMT</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Extension of limited-time promotional discounts on Azure Databricks Serverless Compute Services</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467457</link>
      <description>We&#8217;re excited to announce the extension of the promotional discounts on serverless compute for Notebooks, Jobs, and Pipelines (Delta Live Tables). You will continue to get 50% off serverless compute for Jobs and Pipelines and 30% off serverless compute for Notebooks, until&#160;January 31, 2025.&#160;Serverless compute provides rapid workload startup, automatic infrastructure scaling, and seamless version upgrades of the Azure Databricks runtime.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retirement: End of Support Announcement for Azure Load Balancer numberOfProbes property on September 1, 2027.</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=end-of-support-announcement-for-azure-load-balancer-numberofprobes-property-on-1-september-2027</link>
      <description>Support for Azure Load Balancer numberOfProbes property ends on September 1, 2027. To avoid service disruption, upgrade your apps to API version 2022-05-01 or higher and start using Azure Load Balancer probeThreshold property. We will not be supporting the property numberOfProbes after September 1, 2027.Required actionBefore September 1, 2027, stop using the property numberOfProbes and/or migrate to probeThreshold property.Learn more about updating your API.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=end-of-support-announcement-for-azure-load-balancer-numberofprobes-property-on-1-september-2027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TLS 1.2 to become the minimum TLS version for Azure Storage</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=tls-12-to-become-the-minimum-tls-version-for-azure-storage</link>
      <description>To respond to evolving technology and regulatory standards, Azure Storage will remove support for TLS version 1.1 and 1.0, and the minimum supported version will be TLS1.2 starting November 1, 2025. TLS 1.2 is more secure and faster than older TLS versions. TLS 1.0 and 1.1 do not support modern cryptographic algorithms and cipher suites.&#160;&#160;

This change impacts existing and new storage accounts using TLS 1.0 and 1.1 in all clouds. To avoid disruptions to your applications connecting to Azure Storage, you must migrate to TLS 1.2 and remove dependencies on TLS version 1.0 and 1.1.&#160;

Azure Storage already supports TLS 1.2 which is set as the default. Customers using TLS 1.2 will not be impacted by the removal of support for TLS 1.0 and 1.1. For customers using TLS 1.0 or 1.1, to maintain your connections to Azure Storage, please update your operating systems, development libraries, frameworks, and all other solutions to their latest versions to support TLS 1.2 and update your clients to TLS 1.2 no later than Oct 31st, 2025.&#8239;&#160;

We have compiled a series of recommendations and resources to help with your migration:&#160;Navigate here for more information</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=tls-12-to-become-the-minimum-tls-version-for-azure-storage</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Azure Cosmos DB vector database integration with LangChain.js</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466855</link>
      <description>We&#8217;re&#160;excited to introduce LangChain.js integration with Azure Cosmos DB. You can use this powerful combination to efficiently manage fast and accurate&#160;data retrieval with greater ease in your JavaScript applications. The new LangChain.js integration makes the most of Azure Cosmos DB scalability and efficient vector search capabilities, simplifying applications development and large language model (LLM) orchestration tasks.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466855</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Single prefix enhancement to seamless gateway migration</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467620</link>
      <description>With the Gateway migration experience, customers can use the Azure Portal or PowerShell scripts to deploy a second Virtual Network Gateway within the same GatewaySubnet of the Virtual Network. During the migration phase, once initiated by the customer, Azure will transfer both the control plane and data path configurations from the existing gateway to the newly deployed one. This process will result in two operational Gateways within the same Gateway Subnet. After the migration is successfully completed, customers can remove the original Gateway, leaving the new Gateway in place for continued Private Connectivity.&#160;Previously, ExpressRoute Gateway customers needed to create a second address prefix to pass the validation stage of migrating their gateway. With this enhancement, customers can now migrate with a single prefix, eliminating the previous requirement to create a second address prefix in the Gateway. This feature is designed to support migrations with minimal downtime.To learn more, see:About migrating to an availability zone-enabled ExpressRoute virtual network gateway - Azure ExpressRoute | Microsoft LearnMigrate to an availability zone-enabled ExpressRoute virtual network gateway in Azure portal - Azure ExpressRoute | Microsoft Learn</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467620</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Azure Chaos Studio now supports faults for AKS clusters using managed identity authentication</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467714</link>
      <description>Azure Chaos Studio&#8217;s faults for Azure Kubernetes Service clusters
now work with managed identity authentication. Previously, local authentication
through the Kubernetes API server was the only supported authentication method.
To enable customers with an enhanced security posture for AKS clusters to
perform fault injection, the Version 2.2 AKS Chaos Mesh faults now also support
managed identity authentication. Customers using Version 2.1 faults will need
to enable the new capabilities and modify the relevant experiments to use the
new versions. Version 2.1 faults will be unavailable in the Chaos Studio user
interface on or after January 31, 2025, but remain runnable in experiments
until further notice. Learn more at this link: Using Microsoft Entra authentication with Chaos Studio AKS
faults.&#160;For more information about Azure Chaos Studio, see&#160;Azure Chaos Studio documentation.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467714</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retirement: Azure Health Data Services will be retired on October 31, 2025 in the Qatar Central region</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466779</link>
      <description>Because we're consolidating resources and there is low usage in the region, we'll be retiring Azure Health Data Services the Qatar Central region on&#160;October 31, 2025. Please ensure that you migrate to another available Azure Health Data Services region by that date.Until October 31, 2025, you can continue to use Azure Health Data Services without disruption. However, on October 31, 2025, all workloads running Azure Health Data Services in the Qatar Central region will be deleted, and associated application data will be lost. Below are resources to assist you with your migration.Required actionPlease transition your workloads to another Azure Health Data Services region&#160;before October 31, 2025.View the regions where Azure Health Data Services are available&#160;here.Help and supportIf you have questions, you can get answers from community experts in&#160;Microsoft Q&#38;A. If you have a support plan and need technical assistance, please create a&#160;support request.Azure Health Data Services from the Qatar Central region is retiring as of October 31, 2024. We are asking customers to utilize one of our other regions or remove/backup data they wish to retain before retirement.Customers may use one of our other regions.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Advanced Container Networking Services</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466985</link>
      <description>Advanced
Container Networking Services (ACNS) is now generally available. ACNS includes
Advanced Network Observability, providing pod-level metrics, DNS insights, and
enhanced troubleshooting tools for network debugging in AKS.&#160;&#160;Additionally,
FQDN filtering is also generally available, simplifying network policy
management by using domain names instead of IP addresses. This reduces the need
for frequent updates and minimizes configuration errors. Both features are
integrated with Azure Monitor, enabling customizable metrics and pre-built
dashboards in Azure Managed Grafana, improving network management and security
for AKS environments.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466985</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Delete a specific machine</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466990</link>
      <description>It is now possible
to specifically choose which VM to delete and remove when scaling down a node
pool in AKS. This provides greater control and flexibility in managing
resources within the node pool.&#160;&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466990</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Ignore PDBs on node pool deletion</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466995</link>
      <description>Node pools in AKS can now be
deleted even if there are pods monitored by a PodDisruptionBudget (PDB) &#8211;
previously, the deletion of the node pool could fail due to an unsatisfied PDB.
This enhancement allows the deletion to proceed by ignoring the PDB error that
would previously block the deletion from continuing.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=466995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Fleet OSS announcements</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467013</link>
      <description>Microsoft Azure
Kubernetes Fleet Manager upstream team is making new multi-cluster features
available to any Kubernetes operator.For core multi-cluster workload placement
there is a v1alpha1 release of staged release pipelines
(ClusterStagedUpdateRun) which represents a stage-by-stage update process that
applies ClusterResourcePlacement selected resources to specified clusters. Additionally,
work has started on adding support to the fleet upstream project for
sig-multicluster's ClusterProfile API (KEP-4322).&#160;&#160;In the networking
space, the upstream team is also announcing the v1alpha1 release of
multi-cluster network traffic shifting for public-facing multi-cluster services
using a new&#160; TrafficManagerProfile custom
resource. This new custom resource provides a cloud native method for
interacting with Azure Traffic Manager profiles and related backends via the
TrafficManagerBackend custom resource. Azure Traffic Manager can provide
DNS-based traffic load balancing for endpoints hosted on any public IP,
regardless of where that IP is hosted.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Static egress gateway for AKS</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467018</link>
      <description>Static egress gateway for Azure
Kubernetes Service (AKS) is now in public preview. This feature allows AKS
customers to configure a fixed source IP for out-of-cluster communications
without incurring the significant cost of deploying a dedicated node pool with
a NAT gateway. The static egress gateway enables precise control over egress
traffic, simplifying integration with external systems and enhancing network
security.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Azure Linux 3.0 on Azure Kubernetes Service v1.31</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467023</link>
      <description>Azure Linux 3.0, the next major version
release of the Azure Linux container host for Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS),
is now available in preview on AKS version 1.31. Azure Linux 3.0 offers
increased package availability and versions, an updated kernel, and
improvements to performance, security, and tooling and developer experience.&#160;Learn
more and get started with the Azure Linux 3.0 preview here.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: SeccompDefault support in AKS</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467028</link>
      <description>SeccompDefault is available in public preview as a new parameter through
custom node configuration. &#160;Secure
computing mode (seccomp) is used to restrict a container&#8217;s syscalls that can be
sent to the kernel. This establishes an extra layer of protection against
common system call vulnerabilities exploited by malicious actors and allows you to specify a
default seccomp profile for all workloads in the node. &#160;&#160;There
are two allowed values for SeccompDefault:&#160;Unconfined is the default parameter
value which does not block any syscalls.&#160;RuntimeDefault will block restricted
syscalls in the containerd seccomp profile.&#160;
&#160;The
RuntimeDefault profile allows a common set of syscalls while blocking those
that are less likely to be used or potentially unsafe in a containerized
application. This profile aims to provide a reliable set of security defaults
while maintaining the functionality of the workload.&#160;Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Azure Front Door WebSocket</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467668</link>
      <description>We are announcing the public preview of WebSocket on Azure
Front Door Standard and Premium. WebSocket is enabled by default without
customer configurations on Azure Front Door.&#160;

WebSocket enables full duplex communication between a server
and a client over a long-running TCP connection. It eliminates the needs for
polling as required in HTTP, avoids some of the overhead of HTTP, and can reuse
the same TCP connection for multiple request/responses resulting in a more
efficient utilization of resources. This enables more interactive and real-time
scenarios. &#160;

WebSocket can be used for apps or websites which require
real-time updates/communications or continuous streams of data, such as chats,
dashboard, finance stock info update, GPS, online education, live streaming and
game apps.&#160;

For more details, please refer to Azure
Front Door WebSocket&#160;documentation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Azure Chaos Studio is now available in Canada Central region</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467709</link>
      <description>Azure Chaos Studio is a managed service that uses chaos engineering to help measure, understand, and improve cloud applicaion and service resilience. Azure Chaos Studio Resource Targeting is now available in Canada Central region. For complete list of regions, see&#160;list of regions Azure Chaos Studio is available.For more information about Azure Chaos Studio, see&#160;Azure Chaos Studio documentation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Azure Load Balancer now supports Health Status</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467610</link>
      <description>Announcing the general availability of Azure Load Balancer Health Status, a powerful feature designed to provide detailed information about the health of backend instances in your Azure Load Balancer backend pool.The Health Status feature offers valuable insights into the state of health of your backend instances and specific reasons for their health status, including:User-triggered issuesPlatform-triggered reason codesWith this feature, you can now monitor and manage the health of your backend instances through detailed status reports. This improved visibility into the health of backend pool instances allows for easier troubleshooting and more efficient management of issues with your Load Balancer.Learn more about health status via our&#160;public documentation&#160;or&#160;recent blog.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467610</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Azure Virtual Network Manager user-defined route (UDR) management</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467615</link>
      <description>We&#8217;re announcing the general availability of User-Defined Route (UDR) Management in Azure Virtual Network Manager. This new feature simplifies managing complex routing behaviors by automating UDR orchestration. Through Azure Virtual Network Manager&#8217;s UDR management, users can easily set up routing configurations that define routing rules, allowing automatic deployment across virtual networks. This means users no longer need to manually create UDRs or use custom scripts&#8212;reducing errors and simplifying routing at scale.The UDR Management feature enables users to structure routing rules into collections, each associated with specific network groups, making routing configurations reusable and consistent across subnets or virtual networks. Users can implement custom routing behaviors, such as directing traffic within a hub-and-spoke topology or routing specific traffic types through Azure Firewall. UDR Management thus ensures seamless, flexible routing that adapts to network changes without manual intervention. To explore this new feature and its capabilities and its regional availability, please see the&#160;documentation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467615</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generally Available: Azure Load Balancer now supports Admin State</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467625</link>
      <description>Announcing the general availability of Azure Load Balancer Administrative State (Admin State), which simplifies managing backend pool instances.Admin State enables you to override the health probe behavior for each instance without additional configuration changes to your Load Balancer such as changing network security rules or closing ports.This makes management, especially during maintenance easy, allowing you to set instances as up or down and control connection behavior with no additional overhead.Learn more about admin state via our&#160;public documentation&#160;or&#160;blog.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467625</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public Preview: Azure SQL Database Hyperscale performance enhancements</title>
      <link>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467630</link>
      <description>We are thrilled to announce some exciting performance enhancements for Azure SQL Database Hyperscale. Our latest updates push the boundaries of what's possible in relational data storage, delivering even greater speed, efficiency, and reliability.One key improvement is the increased log generation rate, now boasting an impressive 150 MB/s, up from the previous 100 MB/s. This significant boost means faster data processing and greater throughput for your most demanding workloads.We're also introducing the new continuous priming feature. This innovative caching mechanism ensures consistent performance levels even after a database failover. With continuous priming, you can expect minimal disruption and maximum efficiency, keeping your operations running smoothly.These advancements reinforce our commitment to providing cutting-edge solutions that help you achieve your business goals. Explore the new capabilities of Azure SQL Database Hyperscale and experience the future of data management today.Learn more.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/?id=467630</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
